{
    "id": "bc164c39cffa436498c21ed98013fcb6",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "You must not question .............................. does not concern you.",
            "description": "What means that which.",
            "answers": [
                "what",
                "that",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "My sister reads .............................. she gets some free time.",
            "description": "Both when and whenever are possible here, but whenever is more emphatic. ",
            "answers": [
                "when",
                "whenever",
                "whatever"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Ria is confident ............................ she will win the race.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "what",
                "if"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You have to decide ........................... subject you want to study.",
            "description": "Which and what are often both possible with little difference of meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "what",
                "which",
                "Either which or what"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Aunt Polly suspected ........................ Tom was playing some tricks on her.",
            "description": "The conjunction 'that' can connect the main clause to a subordinate noun clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "what",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": ".............................. she was behaving so strangely was not clear to us.",
            "description": "The question word why indicates reason. ",
            "answers": [
                "That",
                "Why",
                "What"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My grandmother can only walk slowly ........................ she has arthritis.",
            "description": "So indicates the result because indicates the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "because",
                "hence"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "......................... it tried very hard, the cat could not climb the tree.",
            "description": "All of these conjunctions have the same meaning. Even though is more emphatic.",
            "answers": [
                "Although",
                "Though",
                "Even though",
                "All of these"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "........................... you are determined you can succeed in whatever you do.",
            "description": "Whether cannot be used to indicate a condition.",
            "answers": [
                "Whether",
                "If",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The man asked ........................ I could help him.",
            "description": "Both if and whether can be used to introduce an indirect question. ",
            "answers": [
                "whether",
                "if",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She waited in the park .......................... her friends arrived.",
            "description": "Unless means if not. Until indicates time.",
            "answers": [
                "until",
                "unless"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": ".......................... you give me the keys of the safe, you will be shot.",
            "description": "Unless indicates a condition. It means if not.",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Until",
                "Unless"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}